Jonathan Campbell

campbell.jonathanc@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jon-camp/ https://jon.camp/bell/ 610-905-7503

Accomplished Director of Engineering with a proven ability to create revenue-generating applications and establish money-saving processes. Successful track record leading multiple teams via reporting managers. Experience with several software development life cycle implementations (SDLC) with a preference for modern DevSecOps. Practiced in all facets of staffing, including lead generation, interviewing, onboarding, performance coaching and firing/layoffs. Extensive domain experience in the financial and consumer marketing sectors.

- 20+ years of software development experience
- 11+ years of management and coaching experience
- 9+ years managing other managers

Note: Experience has been abbreviated for length. Please see LinkedIn for more details.

Experience

Director, DevX & Infrastructure

The Predictive Index

Aug 2021 - Present (11 mos)

Teams: up to 7 | Reporting Line: up to 33 | Reporting Managers: up to 7

Directed a cross-functional organization focused on platform and infrastructure capabilities for other engineering teams. Domains covered included Full-Stack Development (C#, Angular), DevOps, Developer Tooling, SDET and Architecture.

- Realigned the company's DevOps vision from a hand-off, operations focus to a "pit of success" wherein software engineers were able to self-serve via command line tools, infrastructure-as-code (IaC) and parameterized pipelines.
- Championed a two-quarter, focused effort to convert 90% of manual regression tests to automated UI tests, resulting in a 15% increase in developer velocity.

Director Of Engineering

Urbint

Aug 2020 – Jun 2021 (11 mos)

Teams: up to 3 | Reporting Line: up to 14 | Reporting Managers: 1

Managed multiple full-stack engineering teams across application engineering and DevOps, including up to 14 engineers. Spearheaded an extensive rewrite of the company's flagship Damage Prevention application from a hard-to-hire-for combination of ClojureScript and React to TypeScript and React.

- Jump-started international hiring within the engineering team, resulting in up to 60% savings on salaries compared to traditional New York City rates.
- Championed a mobile-first strategy based on Google Analytics and Pendo insights to provide the best experience for 70%+ of the app's user base.

• Introduced Django and the built-in administration tool to move basic tasks from engineers to deployment specialists, reclaiming forty hours of engineering time each sprint.

Director of Software Engineering

KBRA

May 2013 – Jul 2020 (7 yrs 3 mos)

Teams: up to 10 | Reporting Line: up to 60 | Reporting Managers: up to 5

Led a software engineering organization of up to 60 cross-functional engineers to build, deploy, and support a dozen internal and customer-facing applications through the entire software development life cycle.

- Saved an estimated \$15 million yearly by implementing a new ratings management system. This
 application eliminated the need for hiring additional data entry staffing, increased efficiency for
 ratings publication, and kept the company in compliance with extensive government regulations
- Transitioned 100% of the firm's custom applications from bare metal servers to private- and public-cloud hosting (Azure & AWS) with 80% of those applications moving to Docker and Infrastructure-as-Code (IaC) within one year.
- Leveraged a combination of employees, on- and off-shore contractors, and multiple service providers to successfully build a drop-in replacement for a competitor's product across multiple delivery channels (desktop software, web application, and data feeds) within two years.
- Instituted policies, procedures, and tools to successfully transition the firm from a traditional environment with a wall between engineering and operations to an integrated DevOps culture.

Director Of Information Technology

ReminderMedia

May 2006 – May 2013 (7 yrs 1 mo)

Teams: 2 | Reporting Line: up to 12 | Reporting Managers: 1

Provided holistic technical vision and leadership while managing a staff of up to 12, including support staff, system administrators, and software developers. Served as product owner for multiple custom applications; collected user requirements, created functional and technical specifications, and reviewed new changes with users and stakeholders regularly.

Created a two-year, comprehensive onboarding and mentoring process for new developers.
 Established relationships with multiple local colleges. These two paired together resulted in savings of up to \$45,000 on each new developer hire by placing smart, ambitious new graduates instead of seasoned developers.

Education

Allentown Business School

Associates in Specialized Technology, Personal Computer and Network Technology 1999 – 2001